[music]
>> Hello and welcome. This time I don't
have a laptop and we're going to talk
about supply chain management.
What is supply chain
chain management in Business Central? It
used to be different from the rest of
the world. Actually, it's what we used
to say internally, not finance.
Yeah. So, we have a range of features
and tools from procurement to production
to distribution logistics, everything we
call supply chain management. And in
this release we did a lot of things in
this area.
Let's go through them in this long
screenshot only video just to get an
idea of what is here, what was added or
changed in the Business Central. We will
start with the bigger features and move
to the different stuff.
And we have a secret guest in the very
end.
Stay tuned.
All right. The big big
elephant
is a quality management new extension
available which will automate your
quality management processes and ensure
that you are industry and legally
compliant and your customers are happy
because you always ship the goods which
are in the good quality and you should
because you check them when you received
or produce them.
Very flexible.
Very interesting.
We have a special role at center with
all the different steps etc.
You can always look at the separate
video. The link will be here or here.
And you will learn more
how to use and how to get populated with
quality inspection.
That's a one big thing.
Definitely explore
new model.
Another one group of enhancements are
all related into the drop shipment
process.
Yeah.
Sometimes you sell something which you
do not have on on your inventory because
it is on your vendor inventory and
that's what you want to them to transfer
and ship ship directly to your customer.
So,
what happened?
Now there are more ways to create
purchase documents
for drop shipment sales documents.
Another enhancement is a order of
operation. Originally Business Central
was a bit restrictive about what you can
post first and what you post then.
Now it's becoming more flexible. And
last but not least, undo because
mistakes happens. Can you fix them? With
drop shipments, you can also
do that nowadays. There is a separate
video about it.
Go and check. So, couple of screenshots
just to get you started or interested.
From the sales document we can use the
standard create purchase order
action which normally creates purchase
documents for
items with a normal
buy and sell
flow but also supports drop shipment
scenarios and you can see the new toggle
drop shipment which indicates that all
these lines are created for drop
shipment.
And once
this purchase document created, you can
just go and post it as
receipt and invoice. Do not wait when in
customer facing invoice is posted.
There are more and you will see in the
corresponding video.
Including the undo scenario. Yeah, it's
very difficult to illustrate that this
undo is related to
drop shipment but trust me, it is.
Moving to the next topic.
Purchase order matching. Another great
feature added in this release. You can
always [snorts] ask how it is related to
supply chain. Yeah, because we're
dealing with orders nowadays and
receipts
which is my part.
All right. So, we receive invoice
before order was received.
What do we do? Put it and maybe forget
about it until it will be received? No,
not really. We can already start do the
process in the system. So, you just
create purchase invoice, link to the
purchase order and wait.
Or not.
It depends. Another interesting scenario
is that if you receive invoice with one
line and you have multiple purchase
orders and receipts, you can link all of
them together. Very convenient.
The last but not least, again, you link
invoice to order which is not received
but you can just hit post
and the purchase order also will be
marked as received. Of course, there is
a setting for this one for this on
specific documents because not all
documents allow these scenarios
but check video.
Uh we have a separate one.
That's a very good one. So, the full
illustration
all of the examples, one invoice line
linked to multiple purchase orders and
uh
order receipts even if receipt line is
not here. The last example you can see.
All right.
You can ask like why get receipt lines
are here?
Because if you're not ready to start to
use purchase order lines but you heavily
rely on the get receipt lines processes
you can use filters nowadays.
So, filters are in the vendor order,
vendor shipment, vendor item number
fields now supported.
Filter and benefit from it.
Uh
also the same enhancement is done for
get shipment and service shipment lines
but of course there are less number of
fields you interested in. Probably your
reference is a one of them.
Next topic, document management.
Different enhancements related to
different documents
and how we manage them.
I think we it's better to illustrate
them with a with a screenshots. And we
start in the middle with the sending.
So, now you can send the document, the
posted sales shipment and sales credit
posted sales return as well. And if you
have not configured emails, you can
always add them to attachment. So,
attachment effect box is also new thing
here.
Another case is about purchase
documents, purchase quote to be more
precise and you can see you now can
create purchase quote without vendor.
You still do need contact and you will
create vendor as soon as this quote is
converted to order but before that
you can have multiple quotes maybe
because you have a one demand and a
three different candidates.
No reason to create them as vendors up
front. They will be converted
automatically very similar as it happens
with the sales quotes. You need the
template.
Uh
vendor template otherwise vendor will
not be created.
All right. So, it's another different
way to use purchase quotes.
Uh last one
you probably know this setup if you use
service management. So, sometimes you
create order only per one item. Yeah, so
even if your service contract includes
multiple elements.
So, now this toggle once activated it's
also respected by batch job which allows
you to create to multiple orders
simultaneously. So, the system will
create order by order for each
service item in the service contract.
All right.
Next group of enhancements approvals.
Yep.
Very long
highly voted product suggestions to
actually support approvals in the
item journals and uh
requisition worksheets.
There is a full list of documents is is
listed. How do you start? You go to
workflow templates, select template and
basically that's it. Now you can use it
in the
for example, planning worksheet or
output journal
and the like. So, there are new actions
which allows you to send it to for
approval.
Cancel, see the status. It works very
much the same as in with the journal
lines with the journals, financial
journals.
General journals, the right term.
Uh and
but we only focus on batches, not lines.
Performance reason because we have too
many lines. So, let's let's let's make
sure that we limit the batches. Also
supported in the with the via Power
Automate. You can always use it the as
well.
Product information management.
Interesting. Now our items are got some
extra enhancements. You can watch more
about it in the Shopify videos because
it also very much used in the
Shopify connectivity
but
you can always use it in the with the
standard Business Central as well.
So, one of enhancement is
item statistics which has some numbers
in the different categories for
different periods.
With drill down to an explanation.
Why would we use them?
Uh
if the numbers are interesting, the
copilot summarization will promote them
and you can see them in the summary.
But now go deeper from item to item
variant and it looks like item
because it has pictures now and it has
item attributes. So, yes, item variant
now has pictures and attributes and they
are used by Shopify connector as well.
Next one.
Group of enhancements related in real
supply chain manufacturing scenarios.
And description two in production bomb
and routings.
It feels like we just again made one
field visible in the UI. No, we added
field. Description two was missing in
the production bomb and routing and in
all the consequent tables, for example,
planning or
production orders,
production order component. So,
now description two is really there,
copied from item or work center or
machine center and follows
follows the the path. So,
field here for real. Feel free to use
it.
Uh
bomb
and routing. What next?
I'm closing my routing. Uh
Look familiar.
We added with a warning in previous
releases
to help the user to understand that
they're missing something because it's a
so common when people spend time editing
a bomb on a routing and for just forget
to check the status
to change it.
Now it really it's a it reminds them,
but not everybody needs it because maybe
people do edit, but
don't need to change status.
So, it's now up to
individual user to decide if they want
to see it or not. There is a setting in
the my notifications
which you can decide do you want to be
warned or not.
All right.
Next one with a reference to the past.
Again, yeah, you can do item tracking on
journals, on manufacturing journals as
well.
And we added an Excel as well. So, you
activate item tracking online toggle in
the journal batch including output one.
And now when you calculate when you
dealing with production output, you can
populate serial numbers right there,
right on the lines.
Easy.
But if you use a explode routing action,
you could not benefit from this from
this behavior. Now you can. If item
which you happen to produce is uh
requires serial number tracking, serial
number trackings, then system will
automatically
split the the last output operation into
multiple journal lines ensuring that
quantity is one for each. Now it's super
easy for you to just go and assign each
individual serial number
uh here.
And notice, we have a request approval
action also also here.
All right, it's a reference to the
previous one.
The last one is a bit interesting.
I will ask you a question. Why do we
have line in the inventory posting setup
with empty location and VIP work in
progress account defined?
Except the cases when we do demos and we
are lazy and do not specifically specify
location.
The answer is uh even if you always use
locations,
the capacity, the output, and
uh
the the capacity and overheads of the
capacity, the run time basically and
setup time,
they are posted and WIP account, WIP
account for empty location always.
That's why
I have to configure them the same way
for my specific location where my
consumption of components will be posted
to
and
blank location for output or for for
capacity because once I will finish my
production order
and calculate the goods,
the WIP account needs to be emptied.
And otherwise it will be disbalanced.
So, what we did?
Now we do not need the empty location
because even when we post
uh capacity entries, we know we post
them for specific production
uh
order line where location is known.
Yeah, so we know location. We can use
it. So, it means we can use inventory
posting setup. So, now you don't need to
maintain this strange line or more or
more interestingly, for each location,
you can now use different work in
progress account and accumulate the
cost
in different accounts and then uh we
will transfer it to the output all
correctly without any leftovers in the
in the work in progress account.
That's a difficult one, but
try to experiment and you will see.
Okay, we talk about manufacturing. Why?
Because we're preparing for something
big again, subcontracting. It's not
something you can see on April 1st or
2nd because it will be uh become
available later in the season, but we do
something in the manufacturing
subcontracting already.
So, what is it?
You can see production order routing, we
got a new fact box
with a subcontracting details. And we
also got number of new actions. In
addition to quality management, we also
got the create subcontracting
document which is purchase order
instructing us to buy some services or
actually ask to delegate someone
uh work to someone to produce
is this this item.
But again, before we do that, maybe they
need some items.
Oh, yeah. Then we can transfer it.
We can create transfer order directly
from the purchase
order for subcontracting. All right, now
all items which are linked via routing
link
with a specific subcontracting
operations will be gathered and packaged
packaged in the transfer order and now
we can ship it.
Let's assume we did that and now it's
time to receive.
And this time we are receiving via
warehouse receipt.
Mhm, that's unexpected, but it's great.
We can use the advanced warehouse
capabilities like warehouse receipts
uh for for operations.
But that's not it.
Once we received it and plan to do the
invoicing, we can also uh we can also
allocate item charges for this one in
case this specific vendor or maybe some
other vendor has extra uh cost with it,
insurance, transfer, etc. which we would
like to allocate to this operation. So,
we have a special actions available, get
subcontracting lines.
And we can allocate it and it will be
included into the cost of produced
items.
Cost.
Yeah. So, each operation can also have a
different price tag. So, the same item
produced on different vendors or
different quantities will have a
different price.
Uh processing price.
Meaning
the the costing will be more accurate as
well.
But you need to wait for it and more
details will follow as soon as we are
close to the release.
Thank you for watching. That was a long
list of enhancements and definitely
short one, but you can find different
videos which are explaining more
complicated details in the descriptions
pointing to the relevant videos as well.
Plus, you can always find in the
description additional information, for
example, release note where we can also
add some
details and links to the documentations.
If you have any questions, you can
always reach to us. You know where to
find us. It's LinkedIn and it is now
Viva Engage
plus regular office hours.
Looking forward to talk to you.
Thank you.